<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Recap on MindRL hub</title>
    <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Recap on MindRL hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research Recap | Trait somatic anxiety is associated with reduced directed exploration and underestimation of uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/fan230922/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/fan230922/</guid>
      <description>Recording TBD
Speaker Haoxue Fan
Bio Haoxue Fan is a fifth-year graduate student at Harvard working with Dr. Elizabeth Phelps. She is interested in how emotion interacts with decision-making under uncertainty, including cognitive processes such as exploration, information seeking, and planning. To answer these questions, she uses a combination of computational modeling, physiological measurements, and behavioral experiments. She is originally from Shanghai in China, and is always eager to know where is the best coffee and boba tea place in town :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Recap | Reinforcement learning biases that makes us smart</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/palminteri230915/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/palminteri230915/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1sh4y1A7eu/
Speaker Stefano Palminteri
Bio I am a Research Director (equivalent of Full Professor) and head of the Human Reinforcement Learning team, which is part of the Laboratoire de Neurosciences Cognitives et Computationelles. My goal is understanding how humans learn to make decisions at the behavioral, computational and neural levels. I am mainly (but not only!) interested in situations when decisions are based on past experience (a.k.a. reinforcement learning). In the last few years I mainly worked on two computational hypotheses, &amp;ldquo;relative value&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;learning bias&amp;rdquo;, concerning human reinforcement learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Recap | Working memory guides action valuation in model-based inference</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/zuo230909/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/zuo230909/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Sj411C77e/?vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Zhaoyu Zuo
Bio Zhaoyu Zuo obtained a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in pattern recognition and intelligent systems from the University of Science and Technology of China and is now a research assistant at Shanghai Jiao Tong University. He is concerned with the nature of human intelligence and the mechanisms that lead to behavior and mental disorders. He uses brain-inspired models to study the cognitive computational mechanisms behind complex decisions, particularly the cooperative relationship between memory systems and reinforcement learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Recap | Neural network modeling reveals diverse human exploration behaviors via state space analysis</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/xiong230809/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/xiong230809/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1au4y1R7kh/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Huadong Xiong
Bio I am a first-year Ph.D student in the CNS program, the department of psychology at the University of Arizona, directed by Dr. Robert Wilson. I build models to understand behaviors and I study how computation could be implemented in neural networks. Following the release of GPT-4, my research interest has partially shifted towards understanding the emergence of intelligence within large language models.
Abstract The exploration-exploitation trade-off, balancing the acquisition of new information with the utilization of known resources, is a fundamental dilemma faced by all adaptive intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
