<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>MindRL hub</title>
    <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MindRL hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RLDMJC.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toby Wise | Learning about uncertainty: mechanisms and implications for mental health</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/wise240229/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/wise240229/</guid>
      <description>Recording Speaker Toby Wise
Bio Toby Wise is a Senior Research Fellow in the Department of Neuroimaging at the Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp;amp; Neuroscience (IoPPN) at King&amp;rsquo;s College London.Toby started his academic career with a BSc in Psychology and MSc in Cognitive Neuroscience at the University of Sussex, before completing a PhD at the Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience at King’s College London, where he focused on neuroimaging markers of depression and bipolar disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael J. Frank | Clustering and generalization of abstract structures in reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/frank231214/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/frank231214/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV14i4y1e7Lc/?vd_source=8b926cc5cb9e7d8fb85957e534d96e47
Speaker Michael J. Frank
Bio Michael J. Frank is Edgar L Marston Professor of Cognitive, Linguistic &amp;amp; Psychological Sciences at Brown University. He directs the Center for Computational Brain Science within the Carney Institute for Brain Science. He received his PhD in Neuroscience and Psychology in 2004 at the University of Colorado, following undergraduate and master&amp;rsquo;s degrees in electrical engineering. Frank’s work focuses primarily on theoretical models of frontostriatal circuits and their modulation by dopamine, especially their cognitive functions and implications for neurological and psychiatric disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert C. Wilson | Information, randomization, and simulation in exploration and exploitation</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/wilson231205/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/wilson231205/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1vg4y1f7ey/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Robert C. Wilson
Bio Bob Wilson is an Associate Professor of Psychology and Director of the Cognitive Science Program at the University of Arizona. Bob is interested in the computational neuroscience of decision-making, studying all kinds of choices from simple perceptual decisions to judgments about phishing emails. Outside of the lab, Bob enjoys raising chickens and learning the piano.
Abstract Many decisions involve a trade-off between exploring unknown options for information and exploiting known options for a more certain payoff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weiji Ma | The cognitive science of complex planning</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/ma231201/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/ma231201/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1ye411d7Ty/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=8b926cc5cb9e7d8fb85957e534d96e47
Speaker Weiji Ma
Bio Wei Ji Ma is Professor of Neural Science and Psychology at New York University. He received his Ph.D. in Theoretical Physics from the University of Groningen, the Netherlands, in 2001. He switched to computational neuroscience and computational cognitive science, doing postdocs at Caltech and the University of Rochester. He was Assistant Professor of Neuroscience at Baylor College of Medicine from 2008 to 2013 before he joined New York University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charley Wu | Visual-spatial dynamics drive adaptive social learning in immersive environments</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/wu231108/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/wu231108/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1ZM411S7d7/
Speaker Charley Wu
Bio Charley Wu is a cognitive scientist who is interested in the specific shortcuts and cognitive algorithms that people use to make inference tractable. Using online and virtual reality experiments, He employs computational models to predict and understand human behavior. These models allow us to understand the strategies and approximations that allow people to do so much with so little. Originally trained in Philosophy at the University of British Columbia, He pivoted to cognitive science via a M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taicheng Huang | Beyond the hippocampus as a predictive map</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/journaljam/huang231028/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/journaljam/huang231028/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Cy4y1w7Wx/
Speaker Taicheng Huang
Bio Taicheng Huang (黄泰诚) is a postdoc at Shanghai Mental Health Center, affiliated with Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, under the supervision of Prof. Tifei Yuan (袁逖飞教授). He graduated from Beijing Normal University, and received doctoral training in cognitive neuroscience. Later, he came to Tsinghua University for formal training in cognitive science under the supervision of Prof. Jia Liu (刘嘉教授). Currently, he hopes to dive into psychiatry to integrate psychology, computational science and neuroscience to understand mental illnesses, especially addiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Seongmin A. Park | Structural abstraction and behavioral flexibility</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/park231020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/park231020/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1QN4y1C77n/?vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Seongmin A. Park
Bio Seongmin A. Park is a researcher at the Institute of Cognitive Science Marc Jeannerod, CNRS (UMR5229), where he focuses on human learning and decision-making. He received his Ph.D. from the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology and completed his postdoctoral training at CNRS with Dr. Jean-Claude Dreher and at UC Davis with Dr. Erie Boorm
Abstract Generalizing past experiences to new situations is a hallmark of human intelligence, but it remains challenging for many AI systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt Nassar | Dynamic representations for behavioral flexibility</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/nassar231012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/nassar231012/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1G34y1g7Q6/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Matt Nassar
Bio Matt Nassar is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Neuroscience at Brown University. He received his BA at Colgate University and his Doctorate from the University of Pennsylvania. He completed post-doctoral training at the University of Pennsylvania and Brown University before joining the faculty at Brown. His research examines how the brain prioritizes, segregates, and combines information collected in complex environments and how this process differs across individuals, pathologies, and over-healthy aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Ho | Construction of mental representations in human planning</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/ho231004/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/ho231004/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1P94y1a7Kf/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Mark Ho
Bio Mark Ho is an Assistant Professor in the Computer Science Department at Stevens Institute of Technology. Previously, he was a faculty fellow at NYU and a postdoc at Princeton and UC Berkeley. He received his Ph.D in Cognitive Science and M.S. in Computer Science from Brown University. His research combines approaches from cognitive science, social psychology, and computer science to study the computational principles underlying human problem solving and social cognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haoxue Fan | Trait somatic anxiety is associated with reduced directed exploration and underestimation of uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/fan230922/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/fan230922/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Rh4y1a7iq/?vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Haoxue Fan
Bio Haoxue Fan is a fifth-year graduate student at Harvard working with Dr. Elizabeth Phelps. She is interested in how emotion interacts with decision-making under uncertainty, including cognitive processes such as exploration, information seeking, and planning. To answer these questions, she uses a combination of computational modeling, physiological measurements, and behavioral experiments. She is originally from Shanghai in China, and is always eager to know where is the best coffee and boba tea place in town :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stefano Palminteri | Reinforcement learning biases that makes us smart</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/palminteri230915/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/palminteri230915/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1sh4y1A7eu/
Speaker Stefano Palminteri
Bio I am a Research Director (equivalent of Full Professor) and head of the Human Reinforcement Learning team, which is part of the Laboratoire de Neurosciences Cognitives et Computationelles. My goal is understanding how humans learn to make decisions at the behavioral, computational and neural levels. I am mainly (but not only!) interested in situations when decisions are based on past experience (a.k.a. reinforcement learning). In the last few years I mainly worked on two computational hypotheses, &amp;ldquo;relative value&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;learning bias&amp;rdquo;, concerning human reinforcement learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhaoyu Zuo | Working memory guides action valuation in model-based inference</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/zuo230909/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/zuo230909/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Sj411C77e/?vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Zhaoyu Zuo
Bio Zhaoyu Zuo obtained a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in pattern recognition and intelligent systems from the University of Science and Technology of China and is now a research assistant at Shanghai Jiao Tong University. He is concerned with the nature of human intelligence and the mechanisms that lead to behavior and mental disorders. He uses brain-inspired models to study the cognitive computational mechanisms behind complex decisions, particularly the cooperative relationship between memory systems and reinforcement learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shen Xu | Crash tutorials on fitting hierarchical Bayesian reinforcement learning models</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/tutorialtalk/xu230826/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/tutorialtalk/xu230826/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1qm4y1u7JU/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=1a260a61416c0a766c7c16e727b2f404
Speaker Shen Xu
Bio Shen Xu is a third-year Ph.D. student from the School of Psychological and Cognitive Sciences at Peking University. He studies Basic Psychology under the supervision of Professor Dr. Xiaolin Zhou, and he is mainly keen on millisecond tactile information integration and computational social cognition. For the former, Shen focuses on how different tactile information is integrated and its temporal dynamics in the human brain. For the latter, he focuses on the computational and neural mechanisms of advantageous and disadvantageous unfair decision-making in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/upcoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/upcoming/</guid>
      <description> Title Speaker Time (UTC+8) Type Language Zoom (password) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huadong Xiong | Neural network modeling reveals diverse human exploration behaviors via state space analysis</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/xiong230809/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/xiong230809/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1au4y1R7kh/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Huadong Xiong
Bio I am a first-year Ph.D student in the CNS program, the department of psychology at the University of Arizona, directed by Dr. Robert Wilson. I build models to understand behaviors and I study how computation could be implemented in neural networks. Following the release of GPT-4, my research interest has partially shifted towards understanding the emergence of intelligence within large language models.
Abstract The exploration-exploitation trade-off, balancing the acquisition of new information with the utilization of known resources, is a fundamental dilemma faced by all adaptive intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is MindRL</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
