<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>MindRL hub</title>
    <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MindRL hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://RLDMJC.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matt Nassar | Dynamic representations for behavioral flexibility</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/nassar231012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/nassar231012/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1G34y1g7Q6/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Matt Nassar
Bio Matt Nassar is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Neuroscience at Brown University. He received his BA at Colgate University and his Doctorate from the University of Pennsylvania. He completed post-doctoral training at the University of Pennsylvania and Brown University before joining the faculty at Brown. His research examines how the brain prioritizes, segregates, and combines information collected in complex environments and how this process differs across individuals, pathologies, and over-healthy aging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Ho | Construction of mental representations in human planning</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/ho231004/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/ho231004/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1P94y1a7Kf/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Mark Ho
Bio Mark Ho is an Assistant Professor in the Computer Science Department at Stevens Institute of Technology. Previously, he was a faculty fellow at NYU and a postdoc at Princeton and UC Berkeley. He received his Ph.D in Cognitive Science and M.S. in Computer Science from Brown University. His research combines approaches from cognitive science, social psychology, and computer science to study the computational principles underlying human problem solving and social cognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haoxue Fan | Trait somatic anxiety is associated with reduced directed exploration and underestimation of uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/fan230922/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/fan230922/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Rh4y1a7iq/?vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Haoxue Fan
Bio Haoxue Fan is a fifth-year graduate student at Harvard working with Dr. Elizabeth Phelps. She is interested in how emotion interacts with decision-making under uncertainty, including cognitive processes such as exploration, information seeking, and planning. To answer these questions, she uses a combination of computational modeling, physiological measurements, and behavioral experiments. She is originally from Shanghai in China, and is always eager to know where is the best coffee and boba tea place in town :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stefano Palminteri | Reinforcement learning biases that makes us smart</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/palminteri230915/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/palminteri230915/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1sh4y1A7eu/
Speaker Stefano Palminteri
Bio I am a Research Director (equivalent of Full Professor) and head of the Human Reinforcement Learning team, which is part of the Laboratoire de Neurosciences Cognitives et Computationelles. My goal is understanding how humans learn to make decisions at the behavioral, computational and neural levels. I am mainly (but not only!) interested in situations when decisions are based on past experience (a.k.a. reinforcement learning). In the last few years I mainly worked on two computational hypotheses, &amp;ldquo;relative value&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;learning bias&amp;rdquo;, concerning human reinforcement learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhaoyu Zuo | Working memory guides action valuation in model-based inference</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/zuo230909/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/zuo230909/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Sj411C77e/?vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Zhaoyu Zuo
Bio Zhaoyu Zuo obtained a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in pattern recognition and intelligent systems from the University of Science and Technology of China and is now a research assistant at Shanghai Jiao Tong University. He is concerned with the nature of human intelligence and the mechanisms that lead to behavior and mental disorders. He uses brain-inspired models to study the cognitive computational mechanisms behind complex decisions, particularly the cooperative relationship between memory systems and reinforcement learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shen Xu | Crash tutorials on fitting hierarchical Bayesian reinforcement learning models</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/tutorialtalk/xu230826/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/tutorialtalk/xu230826/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1qm4y1u7JU/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=1a260a61416c0a766c7c16e727b2f404
Speaker Shen Xu
Bio Shen Xu is a third-year Ph.D. student from the School of Psychological and Cognitive Sciences at Peking University. He studies Basic Psychology under the supervision of Professor Dr. Xiaolin Zhou, and he is mainly keen on millisecond tactile information integration and computational social cognition. For the former, Shen focuses on how different tactile information is integrated and its temporal dynamics in the human brain. For the latter, he focuses on the computational and neural mechanisms of advantageous and disadvantageous unfair decision-making in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/upcoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/upcoming/</guid>
      <description> Title Speaker Time (UTC+8) Type Language Zoom (password) Structural abstraction and behavioral flexibility Seongmin Park (CNRS) 2023/10/20 14:00 Research Recap English 96944634664 (509050) TBD Taicheng Huang 黄泰诚 (Tsinghua University) 2023/10/23 TBD Journal Jam Chinese TBD TBD Charley Wu (University of Tübingen) 2023/11/08 16:00 Research Recap English TBD RLDDM Miqing Guo 郭鸣谦 (Radboud University) 2023/11/18 21：00 Tutorial Talk Chinese TBD TBD Weiji Ma 马伟基 (New York University) 2023/12/01 21：30 Research Recap English TBD Compositionality (Exact title TBD) Michael J Frank (Brown University) 2023/12/14 21：00 Research Recap English TBD </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huadong Xiong | Neural network modeling reveals diverse human exploration behaviors via state space analysis</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/xiong230809/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/posts/researchrecap/xiong230809/</guid>
      <description>Recording https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1au4y1R7kh/?spm_id_from=333.999.0.0&amp;amp;vd_source=e9626f9767e6e22ece9d765f34ba01c5
Speaker Huadong Xiong
Bio I am a first-year Ph.D student in the CNS program, the department of psychology at the University of Arizona, directed by Dr. Robert Wilson. I build models to understand behaviors and I study how computation could be implemented in neural networks. Following the release of GPT-4, my research interest has partially shifted towards understanding the emergence of intelligence within large language models.
Abstract The exploration-exploitation trade-off, balancing the acquisition of new information with the utilization of known resources, is a fundamental dilemma faced by all adaptive intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is MindRL</title>
      <link>https://RLDMJC.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://RLDMJC.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
